<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Case-studies on MmogoDigital - More than just websites...</title>
    <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Case-studies on MmogoDigital - More than just websites...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2013 - 2017, MmogoDigital. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Giscoe</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/giscoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/giscoe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-client-brief&#34;&gt;The Client Brief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin &amp;amp; Davis had to redesign Giscoe’s website as part of their digital marketing plans, and needed a tech partner to execute on their designs with a 4 weeks turnaround time before launch. The new website was going to be slick, mobile and clearly showcased Giscoe’s services with a clear call to action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-approach&#34;&gt;The Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Scrum for Software development, our Senior Engineers and a Project Manager working alongside the client’s Graphic Design and Digital Marketing team, we were able to deliver the project on time without issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stack&#34;&gt;The Stack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client wanted to be able to update the site content on their own, so we used our tried and trusted Django. It was a tough project, due to tight deadlines, and the client being particular about what they wanted, and the fact that the designers also had exacting standards that we had to adhere to. It was fun, being challenged like that and finding out just how much we can offer to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, we were implementing a design that had already been created for us by the design firm Benjamin &amp;amp; Davis, and all we had to do was code it in a CMS and make sure the final site was the same as the provided PSDs. We loved the design, its simplicity, the big and bold typography, and above all else the minimalism. You will notice the site doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on big images to look good, there is a clever use of typography and color to deliver a great design.
&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/giscoe-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Giscoe Design&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifti</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/lifti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/lifti/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-initial-idea&#34;&gt;The Initial Idea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial idea of Lifti came from the fact that there are a lot of cars in the Botswana, and most people work and live in the same places. It could be Commerce Park, or Fairgrounds, or Mogoditshane, or BBS etc, so we thought it should be possible for these people to share cars and travel together. Its a win win in the end, you make friends, help others and sometimes make extra cash. Also, people can travel together using the same platform for longer trips, for example during holidays when we all want to go back to our home villages. We thought it would be nice to have a central place where people could find a list of all the lifts available and they can look for one that suits them and make a lift request and travel together.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s a platform where we didnt want to make money, but to simply use technology to connect people and hopefully make the world a better place. There has been a lot of concern recently regarding carbon footprints and global warming, and this is our way of contributing positively towards this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;logo-design&#34;&gt;Logo Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo was commissioned from a local designer. The idea was to have a simple but nice logo, that also has takes some meaning from the idea of Lifti itself. If you notice, the F, the T and the I have a little thing going, in that they could be said to be lifting each other up in a way. The color choices were also important, a grey to represent the idea of the travel industry itself, and the yellow to add a dash of color and playfulness to the whole thing. It worked really well in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#39;case-study-logo&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/logos/lifti.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lifi Logo&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stack&#34;&gt;The Stack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifti was built by using NodeJS in the backend, and CSS, HTML5 and Javascript in the front end. We were tempted to use AngularJS in the front end, but we were concerned about taking too long to bring something to market, for an idea that was mostly experimental and wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be monetized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fonts-used&#34;&gt;Fonts Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all our designs, one of the things we try to nail down as soon as possible is the fonts to use. Proper typography makes all the difference in a design. Normally we try to pair a sans-serif font with a serif font, but in this case we found a perfect combination of sans-serif fonts and bent the rules a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;abel&#34;&gt;Abel&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the headings, we chose Abel, a nice clean Google Font that works well for headings. It is clean and very legible, and makes the headings really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;roboto&#34;&gt;Roboto&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the body text, we went with Roboto, which is the main Google font for Android. It is a very clean and legible font, perfect for body text. It also works very well with our choice for the heading text, Abel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe in simplicity, above all else. When a design is simple, it becomes a lot more usable, and can fulfill whatever use we want it to perform. Clutter on the other hand, hides away important functionalities, and confuses users. We wanted the site to be clean and minimal, so we paired mostly greys for the background and dark grey for the text. We made sure to balance it off by adding bright colors to our buttons so they stand out a lot more. We also made sure to use bright colors for notifications, to make sure we really get our users&amp;rsquo; attention when it really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/lifti-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lifti Design&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nova</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/nova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/nova/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-client-brief&#34;&gt;The Client Brief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nova is a student bursary web app, it connects students with companies that offer bursaries. This is a very important project, because
in South Africa, students are not sponsored by the government, rather they have to either self-sponsor, or get bursaries. A platform that
connects deserving students with companies willing to give out bursaries therefore is very critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stack&#34;&gt;The Stack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used Django for the website, to allow the client to add more content over time. A site like this needs to be kept up to date with new bursaries and new companies for it to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client likes the color green, and also wanted a clean and simple design. We cerainly delivered, and we made sure to keep the site simple and have the content drive the design, not the other way around. The choice of fonts was important, to make sure the content would be clear and legible.
&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/nova-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nova Design&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praekelt Consulting - Telkom</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/telkom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/telkom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-client-brief&#34;&gt;The Client Brief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praekelt Consulting had to redesign Telkom’s website and integrate all the microsites they previously had. To effectively achieve the new design, they needed a dedicated Content Curation team to help with Telkom’s vast products and deals on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-approach&#34;&gt;The Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the requirements and the time sensitivity of the project, we deployed a full time team to work with Praekelt Consulting and Telkom’s product managers from the project planning phase till post launch of what is arguably the biggest &amp;amp; best Telecom eCommerce site in Africa. Our Content team remained with the project post launch to facilitate products and deals updates as per marketing and promotions plans of Telkom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, our work was limited to just the content. Telkom has a very complicated CMS, and has lots of products and deals that change quickly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/telkom-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Telkom Content&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reo Properties</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/reo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/reo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-client-brief&#34;&gt;The Client Brief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of Reo Properties is an old friend, and one day he got in touch because his company had grown and needed a web presence. We agreed wholeheartedly, its important for companies to be on the internet nowadays so they can remain competitive. Reo Properties is a real estate company, they connect landlords with tenants, which is a very big market in Botswana. People are always looking for houses to rent or buy, or they want better houses than the ones they currently occupy, and someone needs to be able to make all these connections.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The site would need to list all their currently available properties, have all the details visible to the user such as the prices, availablity, whether they are for sale or for rent, the location etc etc. The client had a basic idea of the sort of sites they wanted to benchmark on, and what they want their site to have in terms of content and so on. But the task on settling on a design was lef to us, the agreement was we would build what we had in mind, also incorporating ideas from the benchmark websites, then have the client review the site and we would then see whether to revise the design or to carry on with our approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;logo-design&#34;&gt;Logo Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo was commissioned from a local designer, the same designer who did the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/lifti&#34;&gt;Lifti&lt;/a&gt; logo. There had been a previous logo, which we felt had not been done very well, and so we set out to take ideas from the old logo, which the client liked, and to clean it up and make it better. The client likes the idea of a lion, the spirit that the lion represents, and also real estate itself, so the logo had to have these two elements together. They also had gold as their main color, so the logo designer had to use gold in the logo. In the end, it worked very well, and the client was very happy with the new logo, and we loved the results as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#39;case-study-logo&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/logos/reo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Reo Logo&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stack&#34;&gt;The Stack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client wanted to be able to update the site content on their own, and to be able to add new properties as they got more clients, so we needed to set up a CMS for them. We love Django, a Python CMS, and we use that for most of our clients who want a CMS. We then did a short training session for the client after launch so they could update the site on their own.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
For the frontend we used the usual suspects, CSS and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;photography&#34;&gt;Photography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to use imagery from Botswana, Gaborone to be specific, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t just get stock photos because you would rarely find any photos of our beloved city in any of these sites. So we commissioned photos from a local photography company to take photos of some of the best places in the city for Reo&amp;rsquo;s image bank, and we chose some from here to use on the website. The results were stunning, there were some very nice photos that came out from the shoot, which we used for the main slider on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fonts-used&#34;&gt;Fonts Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;source-sans-pro&#34;&gt;Source Sans Pro&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to use one font across the site, we had tried some combos and when we finally settled on Source Sans Pro we found it worked perfectly on its own, which to us meant quicker load times for the site, which is also very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client also believes in minimalism as much as we do, and so the choice of design was easy. We used gold for all the main headings, as it is the company&amp;rsquo;s main color, and for the rest of the site played with shades of blue for different sections to give the site balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/reo-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Reo Design&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unilever SA</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/unilever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/unilever/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-client-brief&#34;&gt;The Client Brief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unilever SA needed to recreate their physical staff kiosks online to allow a “click &amp;amp; collect” process for their employees across all their offices from Durban to Johannesburg. The online store needed to address several issues such as stock availability, data privacy &amp;amp; security, payment, product quantity restrictions and integration with their existing SAP &amp;amp; Microsoft systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-approach&#34;&gt;The Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a deeper analysis of the challenges presented by the client, and observing employees using the kiosks live, we set out to create an omnichannel eCommerce platform that does not only allow the convenience of shopping on the go, but seamlessly integrates with the physical kiosks inventory &amp;amp; Point of Sale systems for real time transactions.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The reason behind this approach was to ensure that the online store works in the similar way as the kiosks without discrepancies that might render the new platform inconvenient, whilst allowing Unilever’s product marketing team personalise promotions based on cart history and behaviour on the platform using the built in CRM we added to platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eButler</title>
      <link>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/ebutler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 17:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmogodigital.com/case-study/ebutler/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-initial-idea&#34;&gt;The Initial Idea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eButler is an internal project, that is being run by our Joburg office. eButler was our first internal project, and has been our flagship product in South Africa so far. The idea is to do grocery shopping for people, using Uber for last mile delivery.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We have found that the idea was very popular with companies that need someone to restock their office supplies, which led to the birth of eButler for business, which has accounted for most of our sales revenue so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;logo-design&#34;&gt;Logo Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo was done by a South African design firm, we wanted a simple logo that also had a cart graphic, to show our shopping roots. We had a logo before, but we found it did not truly represent the eButler brand that we had in mind. The new logo had an interesting typography, and the cart graphic we picked had a bow-tie element, that ties to the idea of a traditional butler.
&lt;p class=&#39;case-study-logo&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/logos/ebutler.png&#34; alt=&#34;eButler Logo&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fonts-used&#34;&gt;Fonts Used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For eButler, we did the classic font pairing, a sans-serif font and a serif font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;montserrat&#34;&gt;Montserrat&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the main headings, we picked Montserrat, a beautiful sans-serif font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;istok-web&#34;&gt;Istok Web&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the body text, we settled on Istok Web. It&amp;rsquo;s a stylish and simple font that works well with blocks of text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design was supposed to be simple, so that the products would stand out. And the use of color had to be smart, so that product imagery would not be overwhelmed by the design. At the core, eButler is a shopping site, and shopping sites are driven by product imagery, and in a way it is easier to design. We decided that we want users to start purchasing as soon as possible, therefore the obvious thing to do was to have the products on the home page, and we decided these had to be the most popular products that other users are purchasing
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Incidentally, we are working on version 2 of eButler, which is informed by all that we have learnt over the past 2 years running eButler. We love the direction its going in already, and we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to unveil it to the rest of our users.
&lt;p class=&#39;screenshots&#39; markdown=&#39;1&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmogodigital.com/img/screenshots/ebutler-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;eButler Design&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>